Juanita Kidd Stout Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Juanita Kidd Stout Papers 1873-1998 1948-1997
MSS84478
Stout, Juanita Kidd, 1919-1998
35,000 items
101 containers plus 1 oversize
41 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lawyer and judge. Correspondence, legal case files, speeches, articles, topical files, family papers, scrapbooks, and miscellaneous papers relating mainly to Stout's career as a trial judge.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Alexander, Raymond Pace, 1898-1974--Correspondence.; Alexander, Sadie Tanner Mossell, 1898-1989--Correspondence.; Alpern, Anne X.--Correspondence.; Blatt, Genevieve, 1913-1996--Correspondence.; Boger, Lawrence L.--Correspondence.; Boren, David, 1941- --Correspondence.; Capers, Jean M.--Correspondence.; Chandler family.; Dickerson, M. Ashley (Mahala Ashley), 1912- --Correspondence.; Hamilton, John W.--Correspondence.; Hastie, William, 1904-1976--Correspondence.; Houston, Charles Hamilton, 1895-1950--Correspondence.; Kidd family.; Massiah-Jackson, Frederica A.--Correspondence.; Nelson, Gail--Correspondence.; Nix, Robert N. C. (Robert Nelson Cornelius), 1905-1987--Correspondence.; Ponder, Henry, 1928- --Correspondence.; Schweiker, Richard S. (Richard Schultz), 1926-2015--Correspondence.; Sears-Collins, Leah--Correspondence.; Smith, Charles Z. 1927- --Correspondence.; Specter, Arlen--Correspondence.; Stout family.; Stout, Juanita Kidd, 1919-1998.; White, Ronald A. (Ronald Avon)--Correspondence.
Organizations
Pennsylvania. Court of Common Pleas (Philadelphia County); Pennsylvania. Municipal Court (Philadelphia County); Pennsylvania. Supreme Court.
Subjects
Courts--Pennsylvania.; Gangs.; Juvenile delinquency.; Trials (Murder)--Pennsylvania.; Welfare economics.
Occupations
Judges.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Juanita Kidd Stout, lawyer and judge, were given to the Library of Congress by her estate and by Tyrone S. Drummond in 2000.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. A drawing has been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division, and video and audiotapes have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. All transfers have been identified in these divisions as part of the Juanita Kidd Stout Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Juanita Kidd Stout are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1919, Mar. 7 Born, Wewoka, Okla.
1939 Graduated, University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa
1942 Married Charles O. Stout (1907-1988)
1944 1945 Secretary to Charles H. Houston of Houston, Houston and Hastie law firm, Washington, D.C.
1949 Graduated, Indiana University School of Law, Bloomington, Ind.
1949 1955 Administrative secretary to William H. Hastie, U. S. Court of Appeals
1955 1959 Private practice, Philadelphia, Pa.
1956 1959 Assistant district attorney, Philadelphia, Pa.
1959 1968 Judge, Municipal Court, Philadelphia County, Pa.
1968 1988 Judge, Court of Common Pleas, Philadelphia County, Pa.
1988 1989 Justice, supreme court of Pennsylvania
1989 1998 Senior judge, Court of Common Pleas, Philadelphia County, Pa.
1998, Aug. 21 Died, Philadelphia, Pa.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Juanita Kidd Stout (1919-1998) span the years 1873-1998, with the bulk of the material concentrated between 1948 and 1998. In October 1959, the governor of Pennsylvania appointed Stout a judge of the municipal court in Philadelphia County while she was a candidate for the post in the Philadelphia municipal elections. That November, she won a ten-year term on the court, thus becoming the first African American woman appointed or elected judge of a court of record or general jurisdiction in the United States. In 1988, when she was appointed to the Pennsylvania supreme court, Stout became the first African American female justice on a state supreme court. The papers are organized in the following series: Personal File, General Correspondence, Legal File, Subject File, Speeches and Writings File, and Oversize.
The family papers of the Personal File include material on Stout's parents, Henry M. and Mary A. Kidd, who emigrated from Missouri and Mississippi respectively to settle in Seminole County, Oklahoma, when the state was still a territory. The family file also includes material on the Kidd and Chandler families and on Charles O. Stout, a college professor and Juanita Kidd Stout's husband.
Correspondents in the General Correspondence series include Lawrence L. Boger, David L. Boren, John W. Hamilton, Gail Nelson, Henry Ponder, Richard S. Schweiker, and Arlen Specter.
Most of the Legal File documents Juanita Kidd Stout's service on the municipal court and the court of common pleas, both for Philadelphia County, and as a justice of the Pennsylvania supreme court. She developed an interest in juvenile delinquency, youth gangs, and welfare while serving as an assistant district attorney for Philadelphia County during the 1950s, and once on the municipal court she was noted for her outspokenness on these issues in the local and national media, for her tough sentencing of recalcitrant juvenile offenders, and for her continuing contact with juvenile offenders she found to be redeemable.
The bulk of Stout's service was as a judge specializing in murder trials on the court of common pleas. Most of the common pleas case files relate to trials or hearings where she rendered a written opinion. These were usually either bench trials, where she sat without a jury and ruled on both the facts and the law in a case, or en banc hearings, the first stage of the appellate process in Pennsylvania, where she sat with other judges to hear post-trial motions. She also retained files about cases in which there was a great deal of media interest, such as the Ira Einhorn trial, or in which she had a special interest in the legal issues or the defendants. Some cases not found in the municipal court or court of common pleas case files are documented in newspaper clippings in the Personal File series.
Stout's tenure on the Pennsylvania supreme court was brief, 1988-1989, because she was close to the Commonwealth's mandatory retirement age when appointed. Much of the supreme court case file is taken up with actions against corrupt or otherwise troubled Pennsylvania judges. In rel. Stout relates to her unsuccessful effort to remain on the supreme court despite the mandatory retirement rule.
Other cases in which Stout was involved include Stout v. Helm, part of the Pennsylvania judicial elections file related to challenges of her nomination petitions when she ran unsuccessfully for a superior court judgeship in 1966, and Stout v. W. W. Norton & Co., in which she successfully sued journalist Linn Washington and his publisher in 1995 for allegedly defaming her in his book on African American judges, Black Judges on Justice.
The estates grouping of the Legal File includes material related to Stout's service as executor of the estate of her close friend, lawyer, and civic and civil rights activist Sadie T. M. Alexander, one of the first African American women awarded a doctorate degree in the United States and the first Black woman to graduate from the University of Pennsylvania Law School and admitted to the Pennsylvania Bar.
Stout tracked colleagues and African American and female pioneers of bar and bench through an extensive biographical file that is part of the Subject File. Many lawyers and judges whose careers she followed were also correspondents, including Raymond P. Alexander, Sadie T. M.. Alexander, Anne X. Alpern, Genevieve Blatt, Jean M. Capers, Mahala A. Dickerson, William H. Hastie, Charles H. Houston, Frederica Massiah-Jackson, Robert N. C. Nix, Leah Sears-Collins, Charles Z. Smith, Arlen Spector, and Ronald A. White.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in six series:
Personal File, 1890-1998
General Correspondence, 1948-1998
Legal File, 1873-1997
Subject File, circa 1900-1998
Speeches and Writings File, 1935-1997
Oversize, 1962-1964
Container List
- Personal File, 1890-1998 (Box 1-9)
  Biographical material, family papers, correspondence, awards, newspaper clippings, estate papers, scrapbooks, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject and thereunder chronologically.
  - Announcements, invitations, programs, and Christmas card lists, 1959-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Awards
    - Black Women in Sisterhood for Action (BISA), 1995
    - Distinguished Daughters of Pennsylvania, 1988-1997, undated, (2 folders)
    - Jane Addams Medal, Rockford College, Rockford, Ill., 1966, 1981-1987, undated
    - Medical College of Pennsylvania/Gimbel Award, 1988-1990
    - Miscellany
      - 1964-1982
      - 1983-1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1950, 1980-1987, undated
    - Oklahoma Heritage Association, Oklahoma Hall of Fame
      - Annual reports, 1981-1984
      - Chisum, Gloria Twine, 1982-1989, undated
      - Correspondence, 1980-1988, (3 folders)
      - Invitation lists, 1981
      - Miscellany, 1961, 1981-1985, undated (Box 3)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1981, undated
      - Oklahoma Heritage, 1981-1984
      - Oklahoma Heritage News, 1986-1988
      - Programs, 1980-1985
    - Oklahoma Women's Hall of Fame
  - Biographical material
    - Articles, 1960-1972, 1983-1989, 1997, (2 folders)
    - Biographical sketches, 1962-1972, 1979-1998, undated, (2 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1975, 1991-1995
    - Newspaper clippings, 1931-1997, undated, (11 folders) (Box 4)
    - Resumés and data sheets, 1961-1979, 1983-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Business cards, undated, (3 folders)
  - Family papers
    - Chandler family miscellany, 1960, 1980-1996, undated
    - Chandler, Rowena M., 1929, 1940-1944, 1973-1981, (2 folders)
    - Chandler, Wayne C., 1988-1993 (Box 6)
    - Chandler, William E. and Salina T., 1890-1991, undated, (3 folders)
    - Johnston, Albert L., 1988-1989, undated
    - Kidd, Henry M. (father), 1898, 1927-1929, 1938, 1954-1959, undated
    - Kidd, Mary A. (mother)
      - Correspondence, (4 folders)
      - Estate, 1970-1976
      - Miscellany, 1905-1975, undated
    - Stout, Charles O. (husband) (Box 7)
      - Biographical material, 1907, 1972, 1979, 1988, undated
      - Correspondence, 1952, 1959, 1966-1967, 1975-1980, 1988, undated
      - Miscellany, 1928, 1934-1988, undated
      - Speeches and writings, 1951, 1978, undated
  - Honorary degrees
    - Drexel University, Philadelphia, Pa., 1972
    - Miscellany, 1966-1988
    - Morgan State University, Baltimore, Md., 1985
  - Logan, Theophillis A., and family
    - Correspondence, 1983-1994, undated
    - Miscellany, 1982-1996, undated
    - Photographs, undated
  - Miscellany, 1960, 1970, 1988, 1996, undated
  - Passports, 1963, 1976, 1980-1985
  - Real estate (Box 8)
    - Missouri, 1965-1966, 1983-1994
    - Philadelphia, Pa., 1950-1953, 1964-1966, 1993, undated
    - Seminole County, Okla., 1958, 1968-1976, 1984-1996, undated, (4 folders)
    - Tulsa, Okla., 1985-1990, undated, (2 folders)
  - Scrapbooks, 1959-1965, (2 vols.) (Box 9)
  - Wills, vital records, diplomas, and school certificates, 1919-1997
- General Correspondence, 1948-1998 (Box 9-24)
  Correspondence with attached material between Stout and friends, professional associates, businesses, and the public related to personal and professional activities and public issues.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1948, Oct.-1963, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1964, Jan.-1965, June, (7 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1965, July-1966, Dec., (9 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1967, Jan.-1969, June, (8 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1969, July-1971, Feb., (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1971, Mar.-1973, Dec., (7 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1974, Jan.-1979, June, (8 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1979, July-1980, Dec., (7 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1981, Jan.-1983, June, (6 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1983, Dec.-1985, June, (8 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1985, July-1986, Dec., (7 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1987, Jan.-1988, Oct., (7 folders) (Box 20)
  - 1988, Nov.-1990, July, (8 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1990, Aug.-1993, Mar., (7 folders) (Box 22)
  - 1993, Apr.-1996, June, (8 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1996, July-1998, Nov., undated, (5 folders) (Box 24)
- Legal File, 1873-1997 (Box 24-75)
  Case files, administrative files, dockets, correspondence, printed matter, topical files, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by court, type of material, or subject and thereunder chronologically.
  - African American judges and magistrates, lists, 1988-1989, undated (Box 24)
  - Bar examinations and private practice, 1950-1959, undated
  - Court of Common Pleas, Philadelphia County, Pa.
    - Administrative file
      - Board of Judges
        - Committee for the New Court House and Criminal Justice Center, 1985-1990
        - Criminal Justice Committee
          - Bias Subcommittee, 1993, undated
          - Court appointed counsel
            - Compensation, 1985-1986
            - Guaranteed fee system
              - 1993
                - Mar.-Apr.
                - July (Box 25)
              - 1996
            - Standards, 1987
          - Event calendars, 1985-1986
          - Homicide Program Committee, 1984-1991
          - Internal Operating Rules Committee, 1974-1986, undated, (3 folders)
          - Judicial Study Committee, 1990
          - Meetings, 1986, 1996-1997 (Box 26)
          - Security Committee, Philadelphia City Hall interim security plan, 1992
          - President judge elections, 1980-1985, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1969, Mar.-1991, Mar., (7 folders)
        - 1991, Apr.-1993, Dec., (9 folders) (Box 27)
        - 1994, Jan.-1997, Dec., undated, (4 folders) (Box 28)
      - Diaz, Nelson A., administrative judge, 1991
      - Forms, 1995, undated
      - Institute for Court Management of the National Center for State Courts, Denver, Colo., 1986
      - Judge accountability reports, 1992-1997
      - Judicial Compensation Committee, 1986-1987
      - Marriages
        - Ceremonies, 1993, undated
        - Certificates (Box 29)
          - A14946-D66562, 1962-1996, (4 folders)
          - Miscellaneous, 1960-1993
          - With attached photographs, C07464-C38207, 1984-1987, (3 folders)
        - Marriage register, 1960-1988
        - Miscellany, 1961-1962, 1968-1969, 1978-1988, 1993-1995, undated
      - Pennsylvania Conference of State Trial Judges
        - Miscellany, 1986-1992
        - Pennsylvania Code of Evidence, 1993
      - Pennsylvania Rule of Judicial Administration 703, 1996-1997, undated (Box 30)
      - Personnel file
        - Correspondence, 1990-1995, (2 folders)
        - Law clerks, 1989-1997, undated
        - Position schedules and position descriptions, 1990-1992
        - Pritchett, Shirley, 1988-1998, undated, (2 folders)
        - Resumés, 1971-1986, undated, (2 folders)
        - Retirement plans, 1976-1981, undated (Box 31)
        - Rutgers University School of Law, New Brunswick, N. J., Clinic in Law program, 1989
        - Teamsters Local 115, 1991
      - Petit juries
        - Charges to jury
          - Notebooks 1-3, 1995, undated, (5 folders)
          - Notebook 4, undated, (1 folder) (Box 32)
          - Notebooks 5-7, undated, (4 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1993-1997, undated
        - Questionnaires and questions, 1989, undated
        - Selection process, 1990-1992, (4 folders)
      - Petitions for counsels' fees, 1981, 1986-1997, (10 folders) (Box 33)
      - Post-conviction procedures, 1993-1994 (Box 34)
      - Statistical reports, 1991-1992, (3 folders)
      - Trial lists, 1996-1997
    - Case file
      - Civil cases
        - Allstate Ins. Co. v. Southeastern Pa. Transp. Auth., 1977-1978
        - Belsky v. Rutenberg, 1976-1981, undated
        - Bortin v. Bortin, 1965
        - Bradley v. Board of Pensions, 1980
        - Brown v. American Home Assurance Co., 1981
        - Brunson v. Thomas Jefferson Univ., 1976-1982, undated
        - Bruynell v. Rollins Outdoor Advertising, 1984
        - City v. Aero Newsstands, 1979
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Barnett v. Barnett, 1970
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Johnson v. Pinder, 1970
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Nelson v. Nelson, 1963-1971
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Palmisanov. Palmisano, 1970
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Peditto v. Peditto, 1969-1970
        - Commonwealth ex rel. Schwartz v. Schwartz, 1969 (Box 35)
        - Cotton v. Dickstein, 1981-1983, undated
        - DiBiase v. Progressive Iron Foundry, 1984
        - Doner v. Jonwitt & Rodgers Co., 1971, 1977
        - Ervin v. Wood, 1977-1979
        - Esposito v. Southeastern Pa. Transp. Auth., 1972, 1979
        - Gallen v. Foster Wheel Corp., 1977-1978
        - Gallette v. City, 1977-1979
        - Gafas v. Liberty Mutual Ins. Co., 1980-1981
        - Gaskins v. Pennsylvania Mfg. Assoc. Ins. Co., 1978
        - Gaudio v. Kelly, 1978-1979, undated
        - Girard Acceptance Corp. v. William H. Scott Engineering Co., 1979-1980
        - Green v. Young, 1985
        - Harvey v. City, 1978-1979
        - Jefferson v. Kontsikos, 1985
        - Jenkins v. City, 1980
        - Jenkins v. Lotstein, 1977-1981
        - John W. Caldwell Corp. v. Van Cor, 1977-1978
        - Kahn v. Children's Hosp. of Pa., 1981-1982
        - Kates v. Commerce & Indus. Ins. Co., 1977-1981
        - Ladzenski v. City, 1979-1982
        - Lessig v. Medical Photography Servs., 1979
        - Mattox v. City, 1975-1979
        - McCall v. Wynnebrook Pharmacy, 1979-1984
        - McLaughlin v. DiOrio, 1972, 1982, undated (Box 36)
        - Miscellaneous cases, 1989-1990
        - Presbyterian Hosp. v. Holden, 1979
        - Quaker City Enterprises v. Ricardo, 1985
        - Ragin v. Royal Globe Ins. Co., 1980-1981
        - Richmond v. Kelly, 1984
        - Spires v. City, 1974, 1983
        - Torres v. Nieves, 1979, 1986
        - United Beauty Supply Co. v. City, 1981
        - Ward v. General Motors Corp., 1979
        - Williams v. City, 1979-1984
        - Wolf v. Long, 1979-1981, undated
        - Wood v. Banks, 1970
      - Criminal cases
        - Case files sent to storage, 1992, undated
        - Cases adjudicated, 1991-1997, (2 folders)
        - Cases affirmed, 1986-1987
        - Cases appealed, 1962-1988, undated
        - Commonwealth v. Adams, 1973-1974 (Box 37)
        - Commonwealth v. Alderman, 1992-1996
        - Commonwealth v. Allen, 1965-1970
        - Commonwealth v. Allen, 1977
        - Commonwealth v. Anderson, 1977-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Anderson, 1986-1991
        - Commonwealth v. Andrews, 1997
        - Commonwealth v. Armstead, 1967-1970
        - Commonwealth v. Artiste, 1968-1971
        - Commonwealth v. Avery, 1972-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Baily, 1966-1971
        - Commonwealth v. Barks, 1978-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Barksdale, 1982-1984
        - Commonwealth v. Basile, 1985
        - Commonwealth v. Baskerville, 1983, (2 folders)
        - Commonwealth v. Battle, 1978-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Belliard-Valvez, 1977-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Belser, 1984-1986
        - Commonwealth v. Bennett, 1969-1970
        - Commonwealth v. Beyah, 1993
        - Commonwealth v. Birdsong, 1989, 1995-1996
        - Commonwealth v. Birdsong, 1990, 1996 (Box 38)
        - Commonwealth v. Bishop, 1977
        - Commonwealth v. Boatwright, 1981-1983, 1990-1994
        - Commonwealth v. Bonaparte, 1972-1978
        - Commonwealth v. Bond, 1971
        - Commonwealth v. Bowie, 1981-1982
        - Commonwealth v. Boyd, 1972-1974
        - Commonwealth v. Bradley, 1979-1982
        - Commonwealth v. Branch, 1977-1978
        - Commonwealth v. Branch, 1981-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Brewington, 1992
        - Commonwealth v. Brock, 1982-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1972-1974
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1974-1976, 1991
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1976-1979
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1979-1984
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1981-1982
        - Commonwealth v. Brown, 1986-1995
        - Commonwealth v. Brunson, 1977-1978
        - Commonwealth v. Brzoza, 1985
        - Commonwealth v. Bunch, 1970
        - Commonwealth v. Burns, Commonwealth ex rel. Burns v. Antonetti, 1976-1986
        - Commonwealth v. Burns, 1985 (Box 39)
        - Commonwealth v. Burton, 1970-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Bush, 1980-1981
        - Commonwealth v. Butler, 1976
        - Commonwealth v. Caliman, 1985-1988
        - Commonwealth v. Camp, 1973-1974
        - Commonwealth v. Cantie, 1973
        - Commonwealth v. Carpenter, 1982-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Carpenter, 1983-1985
        - Commonwealth v. Carriou, 1986
        - Commonwealth v. Cartagena, 1977-1978
        - Commonwealth v. Castro, 1979-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Cherry, 1971-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Cherry, 1972-1977
        - Commonwealth v. Clark, 1981
        - Commonwealth v. Clark, 1968-1971
        - Commonwealth v. Clark, 1983-1985, 1991
        - Commonwealth v. Colding, and related case Commonwealth v. Miller, 1886-1988, 1994, undated
        - Commonwealth v. Cochran, 1971-1977
        - Commonwealth v. Coleman, 1972, 1992
        - Commonwealth v. Coleman, 1970
        - Commonwealth v. Collazo, 1981-1984 (Box 40)
        - Commonwealth v. Collier, 1977-1978
        - Commonwealth v. Collins, 1979-1982
        - Commonwealth v. Cook, 1973
        - Commonwealth v. Cotton, 1980-1982
        - Commonwealth v. Council, 1971-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Crawley, 1984-1991
        - Commonwealth v. Cropper, 1973-1974
        - Commonwealth v. Cureton, 1972-1974
        - Commonwealth v. Czerw, 1980-1984
        - Commonwealth v. Daniels, 1994-1997
        - Commonwealth v. Dasher, 1976-1977
        - Commonwealth v. Davis, 1967-1971
        - Commonwealth v. Davis, 1971-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Davis, 1972-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Davis, 1980, 1986, 1995
        - Commonwealth v. Davis, 1994-1996
        - Commonwealth v. DeBose, 1971
        - Commonwealth v. DeJesus, 1982-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Dekeyser, 1981-1983
        - Commonwealth v. Dennis, 1983-1984, 1992-1994
        - Commonwealth v. DeVaughn, 1993
        - Commonwealth v. Dickerson, 1974-1975, 1990-1992
        - Commonwealth v. Dillard, 1975-1976
        - Commonwealth v. Doerr, 1985-1990
        - Commonwealth v. Dowling, 1975-1977
        - Commonwealth v. Driver, 1971-1972
        - Commonwealth v. Dupree, 1979-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Durant, 1972-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Eaves, 1986-1987 (Box 41)
        - Commonwealth v. Egglestone, 1971-1972
        - Commonwealth v. Einhorn, 1979-1984, 1993-1997, undated
        - Commonwealth v. Emery, 1971
        - Commonwealth v. Epperson, 1975-1976
        - Commonwealth v. Everett, 1986-1990
        - Commonwealth v. Ferbee, 1970-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Floyd, 1978-1981
        - Commonwealth v. Floyd, 1979-1980
        - Commonwealth v. Fontroy, 1984-1997
        - Commonwealth v. Ford, 1972-1973
        - Commonwealth v. Ford, 1975-1976
        - Commonwealth v. Friedman
          - Articles and newspaper clippings, 1990-1993, undated
          - Chronologies, 1990, undated
          - Correspondence, 1992, 1997
          - District Attorney's Office, motions and memoranda, 1990
          - Miscellany, 1988-1994, undated
          - Opinions, 1990
          - Other cases, 1983-1992
        - Commonwealth v. Gadsden, 1975-1976